<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sebastian Juhl</title>
    <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sebastian Juhl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://sebastianjuhl.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>W</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/w/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:59:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/w/</guid>
      <description>The Sensitivity of Spatial Regression Models to Network Misspecification Political Analysis, 28(1): 1-19
Spatial econometric models become increasingly popular in various subfields of political science. However, the necessity to specify the underlying network of dependencies, denoted W, prior to estimation is a prevalent source of criticism since the true dependence structure is rarely known and theories mostly provide insufficient guidance. The present study investigates the effects of this network uncertainy which is a special case of model uncertainty that arises from uncertainty about the correct specification of W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congress</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:49:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/congress/</guid>
      <description>Get a Grip on Yourself! Signaling Cohesiveness Through National Party Congresses (with Roni Lehrer)
Parties&amp;#039; success on Election Day and their ability to subsequently implement reforms is affected by their ability to convey a cohesive image. Consequently, managing the diverse and, at times, conflicting interests within a party is of vital importance for office-motivated parties. Due to the unprecedentedly high levels of media attention, their national congresses provide a unique opportunity to present their internal coherence and preference convergence to the broad public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WoC</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/woc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:49:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/woc/</guid>
      <description>The Wisdom of Crowds Design for Sensitive Survey Questions (with Roni Lehrer and Thomas Gschwend)
Electoral Studies, 57: 99-109
Survey research on sensitive questions is challenging because respondents often answer untruthfully or completely refuse to answer. Existing indirect questioning techniques address the problem of social desirability bias at the expense of decreasing estimates&amp;#039; efficiency. We suggest the Wisdom of Crowds survey design that does not pose a tradeoff between anonymity and efficiency as an alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sonntagsfrage</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/sonntagsfrage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:47:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/sonntagsfrage/</guid>
      <description>Die Sonntagsfrage, soziale Erwünschtheit und die AfD: Wie alternative Messmethoden der Politikwissenschaft weiterhelfen können (mit Thomas Gschwend und Roni Lehrer)
Politische Vierteilahresschrift, 59(3): 493-519
Die Wahlabsichtsfrage, populärwissenschaftlich auch als &amp;#132;Sonntagsfrage&amp;#147; bezeichnet, wird kritisiert, weil mit ihr der Stimmenanteil der &amp;#132;Alternative für Deutschland&amp;#147; (AfD) nicht valide zu messen sei. Wir argumentieren, dass alternative Messinstrumente, die Verzerrungen aufgrund von sozialer Erwünschtheit berücksichtigen, besser geeignet sind. Dazu testen wir erstmalig drei alternative Messmethoden --- das doppelte Listenexperiment, die kreuzweise Randomisierte-Antwort-Technik und die Weisheit-der-Vielen-Methode --- hinsichtlich des geschätzten AfD-Stimmenanteils und vergleichen sie mit der klassischen &amp;#132;Sonntagsfrage&amp;#147;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Policies in Germany</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/epa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:45:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/epa/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 Policies in Germany and their Social, Political, and Psychological Consequences (with Elias Naumann, Katja Möhring, Maximiliane Reifenscheid, Alexander Wenz, Tobias Rettig, Roni Lehrer, Ulrich Krieger, Sabine Friedel, Marina Fikel, Carina Cornesse, and Annelies G. Blom)
European Policy Analysis, 6(2): 191-202
Many policy analyses on COVID-19 have been focusing on what kind of policies are implemented to contain the spread of COVID-19. What seems equally important to explore are the social and political consequences of the confinement policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TTIP</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/ttip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:45:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/ttip/</guid>
      <description>Wheeling and Dealing Behind Closed Doors: Estimating the Causal Effect of Transparency on Policy Evaluations Using a Survey Experiment (with David Hilpert)
Political Science Research and Methods, 28(1): 36-52
The Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP) between the European Union and the United States is highly technical. Still, the negotiations triggered large-scale protests among citizens with very diverse socioeconomic backgrounds. Why has a complex issue such an enormous mobilizing effect although the economic consequences are either unclear or favorable for the participating economies?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralization</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/handbook/</guid>
      <description>Preferences for Centralized Decision-Making in Times of Crisis: The COVID-19 Pandemic in Germany (with Roni Lehrer, Annelies G. Blom, Alexander Wenz, Tobias Rettig, Ulrich Krieger, Marina Fikel, Carina Cornesse, Elias Naumann, Katja Möhring, and Maximiliane Reifenscheid)
Jahrbuch für Handlungs- und Entscheidungstheorie
The health crisis caused by the rapid spread of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) poses enormous challenges to governments around the globe. Far-reaching measures have to be enacted, and even a slight delay can have fatal negative consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESF</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/filtering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/filtering/</guid>
      <description>When Space is Just a Nuisance: A Simple Solution for Spatial Dependence (with Laron K. Williams)
Spatial autocorrelation is a ubiquitous phenomenon in cross-sectional data that poses notable challenges for statistical inference since unmodeled spatial dependence can cause common econometric methods to produce biased and inconsistent param- eter estimates. While political scientists so far predominantly rely on parametric spatial regression models, semiparametric spatial filtering techniques constitute a valuable alternative. By using the eigenfunction decomposition of a transformed connectivity matrix, the filtering approach generates a synthetic proxy variable from a linear combination of judiciously selected eigenvectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/issue_competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/issue_competition/</guid>
      <description>Learning at Home and Abroad: How Competition Conditions the Diffusion of Party Strategies (with Laron K. Williams)
British Journal of Political Science, 52(2): 593-612
How do parties decide when to campaign on valence issues given high degrees of uncertainty? Although past studies have provided evidence of transnational emulation of parties&#39; position-taking strategies, these findings do not directly apply to saliency strategies. Moreover, the exact diffusion mechanism remains largely elusive. Based on the issue saliency literature, this study develops novel theoretical propositions and argues that conscious learning enables parties to infer the relative utility of emphasizing consensual issues during an electoral campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCS</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/mcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/mcs/</guid>
      <description>High-Frequency and High-Quality Survey Data Collection: The Mannheim Corona Study (with Annelies G. Blom, Carina Cornesse, Sabine Friedel, Ulrich Krieger, Marina Fikel, Tobias Rettig, Alexander Wenz, Roni Lehrer, Katja Möhring, Elias Naumann, and Maximiliane Reifenscheid)
Survey Research Methods, 14(2): 171-178
The outbreak of the COVID-19 pandemic has a massive impact on society. To curb the spread of the SARS-CoV-2 virus, unprecedented containment measures are being taken by governments around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEA</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/eigenfunctions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/eigenfunctions/</guid>
      <description>Spatial Eigenfunction Modeling of Geo-Referenced Data in the Social Sciences Many phenomenon of interest to social scientists exhibit some non-random spatial patterning. While the geographic distribution of variables can reveal valuable information about the underlying mechanisms, unaccounted spatial autocorrelation simultaneously causes severe problems for common econometric methods as it may lead to biased and inconsistent parameter estimates. In order to safeguard against false inferences and to utilize the spatial information contained in a variable, it is imperative for quantitative social scientists to apply appropriate techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spfilteR</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/spfilter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/spfilter/</guid>
      <description>spfilteR: An R Package for Semiparametric Spatial Filtering with Eigenvectors in (Generalized) Linear Models The R Journal, 13(2): 450-459
Eigenvector-based spatial filtering constitutes a highly flexible semiparametric approach to account for spatial autocorrelation in a regression framework. It combines judiciously selected eigenvectors from a transformed connectivity matrix to construct a synthetic spatial filter and remove spatial patterns from model residuals. This article introduces the spfilteR package that provides several useful and flexible tools to estimate spatially filtered linear and generalized linear models in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/unity/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the Relative Influence of Party Unity on Vote Choice: Evidence from a Conjoint Experiment Political Science Research and Methods (First View): 1-9
Observational studies and anecdotal evidence suggest that party unity improves a party&#39;s electoral performance. Yet, due to a lack of experimental evidence, the causal standing of these findings remains unclear. Moreover, party unity manifests in various ways and we do not know how much different types of party unity affect the vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VoterPreferences</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/voterpreferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/voterpreferences/</guid>
      <description>The Economic Roots of Cross-National Similarity in Voter Preferences (with David Fortunato &amp;amp; Laron K. Williams)
Anecdotal evidence and recent empirical research suggest that parties observe the strategies of international counterparts when crafting their campaign messages—a process assuming that (changes in) voter preferences are cross-nationally linked. However, the extent to which voter preferences are correlated, and why they may be correlated, remains contested. We propose a theory that identifies globalization, or, international connectedness, as the principal driver of the observed similarity in voters’ ideological preferences across national borders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wald</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/wald/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/wald/</guid>
      <description>The Wald Test of Common Factors in Spatial Model Specification Search Strategies Political Analysis, 29(2): 193-211
Distinguishing substantively meaningful spillover effects from correlated residuals is of great importance in cross-sectional studies. Both forms of spatial dependence not only hold different implications for the choice of an unbiased estimator but also for the validity of inferences. To guide model specification, different empirical strategies involve the estimation of an unrestricted spatial Durbin model and subsequently use the Wald test to scrutinize the non-linear restriction of common factors implied by pure error dependence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measurement Uncertainty</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/measurement_uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:20:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/measurement_uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>Measurement Uncertainty in Spatial Models: A Bayesian Dynamic Measurement Model Political Analysis, 27(3): 302-319
According to spatial models of political competition, parties strategically adjust their ideological positions to movements made by rival parties. Spatial econometric models have been proposed to empirically model such interdependencies and to closely convert theoretical expectations into statistical models. Yet, these models often ignore that the parties&#39; ideological positions are latent variables and, as such, accompanied by a quantifiable amount of uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 10:02:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Research  Publications Journal Articles (Peer-Reviewed)  Lehrer, Roni, Pirmin Stöckle &amp; Sebastian Juhl (2022): Assessing the Relative Influence of Party Unity on Vote Choice: Evidence from a Conjoint Experiment. Political Science Research and Methods (First View): 1-9.
[Details | Replication Materials]
 Juhl, Sebastian &amp; Laron K. Williams (2022): Learning at Home and Abroad: How Competition Conditions the Diffusion of Party Strategies. British Journal of Political Science 52(2): 593-612.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 10:02:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/software/</guid>
      <description>Software  spfilteR R package
Semiparametric Spatial Filtering with Eigenvectors in (Generalized) Linear Models Tools to decompose (transformed) spatial connectivity matrices and perform supervised or unsupervised semiparametric spatial filtering in a regression framework. The package supports unsupervised spatial filtering in standard linear as well as some generalized linear regression models.
[CRAN | GitHub | Website]
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 14:57:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Presentations  Conferences  Spatial Filtering with Synthetic Proxy Variables in Generalized Linear Models
EPSA 2020, Prague (Czech Republic): 18 - 20 June, 2020
--- Eigenvector-Based Semiparametric Filtering of Spatial Autocorrelation in Linear Regression Models
MPSA 2020, Chicago, IL (USA): 16 - 19 April, 2020
--- Spatial Eigenfunction Modeling of Geo-Referenced Data in the Social Sciences
EPSA 2021, Virtual Conference: 24 - 25 June, 2021
Eigenvector-Based Semiparametric Filtering of Spatial Autocorrelation in Regression Models</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 14:45:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum Vitae  You can access my CV here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 09:42:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About  I grew up in a small village directly adjacent to the city of Hamburg, Germany. I hold a bachelor&#39;s degree in Social Sciences from the Justus-Liebig University Gießen and a master&#39;s degree in Political Science with a focus on on quantitative methods and comparative politics from the University of Mannheim. In the summer of 2020, I completed my doctoral studies at the Center for Doctoral Studies in Social and Behavioral Sciences (CDSS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>http://sebastianjuhl.com/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 09:42:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebastianjuhl.com/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy Personal data (usually referred to just as &#34;data&#34; below) will only be processed to the extent necessary and for the purpose of providing a functional and user-friendly website, including its contents, and the services offered there.
Per Art. 4 No. 1 of Regulation (EU) 2016/ 679, i.e. the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter referred to as the &#34;GDPR&#34;), &#34;processing&#34; refers to any operation or set of operations such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation, alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment, or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction performed on personal data, whether by automated means or not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
